[Music]
my name is Alexa driansky and I'm a
senior software engineer in the business
Central team in
Copenhagen today I'll talk about cost
adjustment and a new capabilities
business Central has to offer
to keep the cost of inventory accurate
and up to
dat first I'll recall what the cost
adjustment is for and name the main
issues a customers are facing then we'll
get familiar with the inventory cost
adjustment tool and how to ensure
uninterrupted adjustment of items
production and assembly
orders finally we'll look at what
actions you I want to take in case
something goes wrong so let's
start the cost adjustment is a key
functionality in the inventory valuation
in the
system so it's aimed at achieving three
main goals first it transfers cost from
inbound to outbound entries which means
that the cost of such outbound entries
such as
sales consumption negative inventory to
adjustment outbound transfers and
purchase returns will only become
accurate after the cost adjustment is
run two it calculate the cost of
production and assembly output as a sum
of their
components Plus for production capacity
used for work and machine
centers and three it distributes
additional
expenses such as item charges and
revaluation
down across outbound
entries how and how often do you run the
C
adjustment the answer
depends on the business needs and the
loow of the system our goal is to find
the right balance between performance
and timeliness of Coast update business
Central offers three no now four ways to
run the cost
adjustment
I would suggest that you go live with
automatic cost adjustment on posting
each
transaction then when the number of
entries posted Each Day become
significant switch to running C
adjustment by schedule in non- business
hours in special occasions like
inventory counting or closing inventory
period or revaluations there would be an
additional need to run the the course
adjustment and now when the course
adjustment work becomes visible for you
and you want to make sure that there
going to be no surprises at important
time we're offering a new way to run and
manage C adjustment the inventory C
adjustment
tool speaking of issues what might
actually go
wrong based on our
experience I would highlight the
following tops
first going live with no Coast
adjustment schedule it may result that
the cost adjustment is not running for
say several
months and it would take hours of cost
adjustment work to get back to normal
state two just one item failing to
adjust rolls back the entire transaction
so all other
items
remaining
unadjusted and the cost is not accurate
which is not
good the functionality has never
been comprehensive to
users and addressing issues often
required Partners help or filing a
support ticket to Microsoft the
performance of the cost adjustment has
never been a strong s but the key Point
here
is it's usually one or just a couple of
items to blame and it's important to
find and isolate them and finally the
cost
adjustment expects
consistent and correct data and high
extensibility of our code made it
possible to feed inconsistent data to
cause adjustment and it may result in
errors or bad performance
to T respond to these challenges we are
now presenting the inventory cost
adjustment tool a new tool for
monitoring the outcome and performance
of cost adjustment to begin with go to
inventory setup and choose one of two
options in Coast adjustment login field
errors
only will log only those Coast
adjustment run that fail and all will
give you the full picture and now
off we go for a demo the main page of
the inventory cost adjustment tool is a
list of items with their cting
parameters you can shorten this list by
using show high filters either focus on
items that are not adjusted
yet
or on those that are excluded from the
cost
calculation run Coast adjustment action
will run the procedure immediately
mediately or later for one item items
you select all items or specially set up
item batches under item you'll find item
entries with additional action to adjust
entries that are applied to the entry
you
choose then we added two pages for this
tables used internally for the cost
adjustment and it is very important to
track the information on these tables
because they contain data about periods
location variance production and
assembly orders that have been or will
be
adjusted what lies under Lo per
functions and Diagnostics we'll see in
just a second let's start and adjust our
items I run the course adjustment for
all
items
so far so
good so let's view the items that are
not
adjusted okay we just have three items
not adjusted because there excluded from
the cost
calculation let's see the outcome and
performance of this cost adjustment run
we go to log per
item and see the time it took took to
complete the adjustment and the Cod
difference it resulted in value entries
will give me
details I might want to go deeper and
investigate the adjustment per
item then I go to lock per item or I can
just drill down to any items I'm
interested in so here we are we see that
the cost adjustment of this item
resulted in this cost difference and I
also can see the
details now let's take a look at a
second not so bright scenario in second
scenario we run the cost adjustment
again for all
items and it fails you can see by using
show ey filters that we have a lot of
items not adjusted with a cost not
accurate which is not good
so what shall we do go to look per
run and we get information about which
exact item failed we will see the error
message here and the error call St so
now I have two options to
continue I can either isolate this
item by using exclude item from
adjustment action or I may I asked
myself a question what if there is more
than just one item that failed how do I
detect all items and make sure that all
other items are
adjusted and here comes item
batches I will add all items in my list
to the
batch go to item batches and run the Cod
adjustment for this
batch please note that the cost
adjustment for batches are running in
separate sessions so each batch is
executed separately in separate
session this is done to properly handle
a timeout periods here but on the other
side you have to use refresh button to
see the latest
result okay looks like the job is
finished let's close the patches and go
to show hide filters to see what we have
left you'll see that apart from those
items that were excluded from cast
calculation item batches identified two
items that
failed and how did item batches do
it if we open item batches again we'll
see that initially they were all items
in one batch then one the cost
adjustment ran into the problematic item
it isolated this item and created a
second batch for all other
items the process is repeated as many
times as you define in maxr try
attempts so finally it ended
successfully and found two items with
issues now we can isolate them from the
cuse adjustment until we find the root
cause
let's go one step back and see why we
believe that continuous monitoring of
course
adjustment and quick reactions to issues
is important for business we're trying
to
achieve two main
goals first we want to minimize or even
eliminate items with inaccurate
cost
then we're reducing the time between
posting an entry and reflecting its cost
in the general ledure having cost
adjustment
logged allows us to properly set the
frequency of the cost adjustment to
align with your business needs locate
items that fail or that have high
performance impact isolate them and
ensure that all other items keep on
being
adjusted and promptly take corrective
actions let's take a look at what
diagnostic capabilities the new tool
provides export and import item data you
can export the item the problematic item
with all its dependencies all related
item tables to text file then you use a
Sandbox environment to upload this
information and focus on investigating
this item or you Cann
attach this text file to the support
request or hand it over to the partner
you're working
with reset course is adjusted reset this
toggle on items production and assembly
orders so they will be taken over by the
next Co adjustment run coting issues
detection report will identifi data
inconsistencies and most common problems
with data that our customers have run
into
before delete item data is a purely
sandbox
action that prepares a clean
environment where you can later upload
the information from the first step and
focus on investigating this item without
being interfered by other
items and and that's it that conclude
the demo but begin the conversation so
do you have a question or you want to
come up with some ideas feel free to
reach out to me on Yammer or on akms
slpc ideas website thank you for today
and let's make friends with Coast
adjustment
together